transum.org 2018-12-06

# Privacy

Transum is passionate about the learning of Mathematics and providing teachers with fresh, colourful and interesting resources to use in the classroom. In order to facilitate the use of some resources a limited amount of personal data may be collected and the following statements explain how this data is used and how your privacy is protected.

For 'Transum Trophies' you are invited to enter your email address simply because that is a guaranteed unique identifier. Email addresses entered will not be used for any other purpose. An alternative option of choosing a Transum username is also available for those who do not wish to use their email addresses.

Teachers using Class Admin or Random Students applications are advised to use student first names or nick names to further protect privacy/anonimity.

Transum subscriber's data remains in the live database for a period of time after the expiry of the subscription period in case a resubscription is later considered.

## Cookies

Transum uses cookies for the 'Class Admin' application which stores email address and password on your local computer so that you don't need to log-in each time you visit a Class Admin page. This information is not used for any other purpose. This facility is only used if the 'remember me' box is ticked.

## Advertising

On some pages we use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and would like to know your options in relation to not having this information used by these companies.

  * Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site. 
  * Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet. 
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/). 

## GDPR

The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) legislation lays out six principles for processing of personal data. These are:

  * **Lawfulness, fairness and transparency.** This covers the primary areas of concern that data should be gathered and used in a way that is legal, fair and understandable. The public have the right to know what is being gathered and have this corrected or removed. Transum will do the necessary correcting or removing of any relevant data within two working days of the request.
  * **Purpose limitation.** Transum only uses data for legitimate purposes made clear at the time of collection. This data is not shared with third parties.
  * **Data minimisation.** The data collected by Transum is limited only to what is required for the purpose stated. Transum does not collect data en masse without purpose.
  * **Accuracy** Transum makes every effort to ensure that any data collected is accurate, kept up to date, and, if it is no longer accurate, is rectified or erased.
  * **Storage limitation** Personal data is only stored online for as long as is necessary. Data may be archived securely and used for research purposes in the future. Where possible, the personally identifiable information is removed to leave anonymous data. The data entered into the database during a subscription request and subsequently by a subscriber into the Class Admin facility is deleted three years after the expiry of the subscription or earlier on request.
  * **Integrity and confidentiality.** Personal data is held in a safe and secure way on the GoDaddy servers. This website hosting company and Transum take reasonable steps to ensure the security of this information and to avoid accidental loss, misuse or destruction.

## COPPA

The US Congress enacted the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) in 1998 and Transum complies by not collecting personal information from children using this site. In particular one feature of the Transum website is allowing users to claim virtual trophies for activities they complete. In order to record which trophies a person has been awarded we ask for a username (but no other information) which could be a made up unique name or an email address. For children under 13 this qualifies as an exception to obtaining prior parental consent as described in the frequently asked questions at http://business.ftc.gov/documents/Complying-with-COPPA-Frequently-Asked-Questions which states that websites may collect a child's email address to be used to authenticate the child if the website does not collect any personal information from the child other than the child's email address and the child cannot disclose any personal information on the website and the email address is altered and not used to contact the child.
